Kishan Narotam



EDUCATION

Software Development

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (Electrical) Information

University of the Witwatersrand Johannesburg, South Africa 2019

IEB National Senior Certificate with Advanced Programme Mathematics

St John's College Johannesburg, South Africa 2012

INDUSTRIES

Logistics & Market Research

Education & Training

ICT (Information & Communication Technologies)

Engineering

Insurance

Banking

TOTAL SERVICES DEMOGRAPHICS

Gender · Male

Disability · None

Race · Indian

Languages · English

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Information (Electrical) Engineer currently employed as an *Associate Consultant* at *IQbusiness*, with a drive in the corporate environment and the desire to apply himself to his maximum potential. Having worked on various projects where his role ranged from lead engineer to a business analyst and to a data analyst, Kishan's approach to work is methodical and analytical. The execution of the task is planned accordingly, to complete all objectives in the most efficient and successful manner so that the maximum value can be added.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate Consultant · IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa # 29/01/2020 - Current

Responsibilities: Kishan was part of the BasIQs programme within IQbusiness. He has worked as a business analyst on an internal project as well as an external project. He has successfully performed the role of a Data Analyst for Genex Insights and is currently an analyst at Absa Group Limited.

Teaching Assistant · University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

07/2019 - 10/2019 07/2018 - 10/2018

Responsibilities: Kishan was required to help run, execute and demonstrate laboratories and tutorials. In doing so he required extensive knowledge of C++, SFML, GitHub and Git collaboration. Throughout the course, Kishan assisted the students in a variety of ways relating to their work.

Intern · Liberty Life Head Office | Johannesburg, South Africa

07/2017

28/11/2016 - 18/01/2017

06/05/2016 - 17/06/2016

Responsibilities: Kishan worked in the IT department of the company assisting the HOD in various projects. The projects tasked to Kishan ranged from data collection, database management, network mapping, system analysis, C++ and VBA programming and Excel programming.

Responsibilities: Kishan was challenged with analysing C# code for an ongoing project and was tasked with converting the project into C++. Following this, Kishan had to design and implement a basic user interface for the analysed code.

Kishan Narotam

TOOLKIT

Software Development

MATLAB · C++ · Java · HTML · CSS · NodeJS · Assembly · Python

Project Management

Scrum · Kanban · MS Project · Trello · Test Driven Development

Databases

MySQL · MS Access

Continuous Integration

Git

Analysis

MS Excel · Power BI · Tableau

Technical Writing

MS Word · MS PowerPoint · MS Outlook · MS Visio · LaTeX

Graphical Editing

Adobe Premiere Pro



ICAgile

ICAgile Certified Professional · 04 May 2020

Tableau Author · 29 May 2020 Tableau Consumer · 26 May 2020

UiPath Academy

RPA Business Analyst Foundation · 12 May 2020 RPA Starter Training · 03 March 2020

Udemy

The Complete Power BI Practical Course 2020 · 08

The Business Intelligence Analyst Course 2020 · 19

Complete Introduction to Business Data Analysis · 09 March 2020

ECDL Foundation

International Computer Driving Licence (ICDL) · 04



in /in/kishan-y-narotam/

/KNarotam

== PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Analyst · Model Risk Data Discovery and Design Absa Group Limited | Johannesburg, South Africa

28/07/2020 - Current

Project Overview: The model risk architecture and processes for credit regulatory reporting are sub-optimal in terms of business efficiencies being realised across the value chain. The project team will develop a target architecture and roadmap in order to identify opportunities for unlocking sustainable efficiency.

Responsibilities: Kishan is an analyst, playing a supporting role to the team.

Data Analyst · MultiChoice Africa Genex Insights | Johannesburg, South Africa

09/03/2020 - 31/07/2020

Project Overview: The project involved working on the MultiChoice Africa account within the CX team, where the data's integrity had to be investigated and monitored. In conjunction to this assisting the team in applying various methodologies that would allow the team to become more proactive in handling the account, and to improve relationships between the MultiChoice Africa and Genex Insights.

Responsibilities: Kishan was placed as a Data Analyst within the Genex Insights' CX team initially investigating a data discrepancy issue, utilising the Genex Insights VOC platform to assist with data retrieval, mapping & managing for MultiChoice Africa. Kishan also updated & created new dashboard views for surveys that had existed & were introduced respectively. Kishan's understanding of the platform gave him the opportunity to train new MultiChoice members on using the platform, while handling queries daily.

Business Analyst · IObusiness Talent Management Solution IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa

06/02/2020 - 25/02/2020

Project Overview: IQbusiness required a proposal for a solution which would aid in the improvement of their current talent management processes, allowing employees and managers to monitor personal development and talent.

Responsibilities: Kishan was part of the business requirements team, whose responsibility was focused on creating the business requirements document, by consolidating prior teams work. Kishan was also part of the governance team and took control of consolidating the project initiation document for the final proposal, as well as presenting the final proposal.

Business Analyst · IAM AfricaAccess | CSO Testing Proposal Absa Group Limited | Johannesburg, South Africa

30/01/2020 - 04/02/2020

Lead Engineer · Design of a Thermally Controlled System for Medications University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

17/09/2019 - 25/10/2019

Co-Lead Engineer · Image Compression Based on Non-Parametric Sampling in Noisy Environments

University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

01/07/2019 - 11/09/2019